# SHADAB SHAIKH (M)

EMBEDDED SYSTEMS ENGINEER

#### EXPERIENCE

# **WORKING STUDENT - AUTOMATION SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

TESTIA GmbH, Bremen Germany

01/2024 - Current

- Development of Automation Tasks in Python for Synchronisation of user information across various company databases
- Managing mobile devices directory using GLPI
- Assisting in various other smaller day to day tasks

#### **SENIOR ENGINEER - EMBEDDED SYSTEMS**

NHANZ SYSTEMS PVT. LTD., Bangalore, India 07/2020 - 03/2023

- Development of Full Software Architecture of a Motor Controller for EVs
- Research on optimizing the efficiency of the Motor Control Algorithms
- Module Testing using Ceedling Unit Test for Test Driven Development
- Defining the HSI (Hardware Software Interface) for the Motor Controller Platform
- Performance Testing of the Inverter Hardware
- Bootloader Port and Flash Programming

# EMBEDDED SYSTEMS DEVELOPER (TCU APPLICATION)

INMOTIVE INC., Bangalore, India 07/2020 - 07/2022

- Firmware development for TMS570 Microcontroller Platform
- Transmission Control software reprogramming
- Curtis Motor Controller reprogramming
- System Testing on Dynamometer

#### FIRMWARE DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

BIODESIGN INNOVATION LABS, Bangalore, India 05/2020 - 07/2020

- State-machine development for HMI frontend and backend programming
- Defining the HSI for a Ventilator Controller Architecture
- Servo Motor Control Programming and UART Communication interfacing.
- Product Validation testing

# CONTACT

### shadab-shaikh.de

017647152503 shadabsshaikh205@gmail.com me@shadab-shaikh.de Rudolfstraße 7 27570 Bremerhaven

# ABOUT ME

Motivated Student currently pursuing a master's degree in Embedded Systems Design. Valuable working experience in the research and development of software architecture, design and testing of products. Comprehensive knowledge in the field of Embedded Systems and Computer Programming.

Date of Birth: 20.05.1996

Nationality: Indian Family Status: Single

# EXPERTISE

#### Languages

**English: Professional Proficiency** 

German: Good

#### Software-Expertise

C/C++: Excellent

MATLAB/SIMULINK: Very Good

Python: Good

# Other-Skills

Motor Control Algorithms
Electric Vehicle Architecture
Image Processing
Real Time Operating Systems
Model Based Design
HIL/SIL Testing

**ARM Microcontrollers** 

#### EXPERIENCE

#### **EMBEDDED SYSTEMS ENGINEER**

EMFLUX MOTORS PVT. LTD., Bangalore, India

07/2018 - 04/2020

- Direct Software Development for the EMFLUX ONE Electric Motorbike
- Simulink based Model Design of the Motor Controller Algorithm
- Induction Motor Control Algorithm Development
- Data Acquisition Software in Embedded Linux & Hardware Development
- CAN Communication Architecture Design for Prototype ECU/Master Controller

# EDUCATION

# Masters in Embedded Systems Design

Hochschule Bremerhaven, (Bremerhaven, Bremen)

04/2023 - today

<u>Topics of focus</u>: Digital Systems, Discrete Control Systems, VHDL, Model Based Design

# Semester Project: Autonomous Car

- Requirements and Specification analysis
- The trajectory of an autonomous car was modelled in MATLAB
- Implemented on HARDWARE using Lego Mindstorm Platform

#### **Bachelors in Electronics and Communication**

Savitribai Phule Pune University, (Pune) 09/2014 - 07/2018

<u>Topics of focus</u>: Analog Circuits, Communication, Digital Systems, Control Systems, Image Processing

# Project: e-Health Monitoring using rPPG:

- Contactless Heart rate detection using video of Human Face
- Algorithm Design in MATLAB
- Digital Signal Processing
- Image Processing

# EXPERTISE

Other-Skills

Bootloader

**CAN Communication** 

Documentation

Date: 28/03/2024

Signature:

